[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 28]
[This story is purely fictional]
[Huo's Secondary Residence, Changsha Suburb]
Fifth Master,
stop walking back and forth.
It annoys me.
Still no news from the city?
Relax.
Master Zhang
has a plan.
Anyway,
it's almost done.
We can eat soon.
I don't have the appetite.
You can eat.
Where are you going?
Dear Godfather,
the south is in turmoil.
Our southern transportation route was suddenly sealed by the officials.
My companions from the Mystic Nine have been accused of thievery.
Our movement is very much limited,
and we are in great danger.
I seek your assistance to release a statement
clarifying the legal status
of our goods
so that the seal can be lifted.
Your help is much appreciated.
Miss Huo.
Send this telegram to Beiping.
Don't let anyone find out.
Should I congratulate you
on your promotion?
There's nothing to celebrate.
This position
means more duties and restraints.
Thank you.
Have you
paid attention to the goings-on lately?
The situation is tense.
We will go to war with Japan soon.
Therefore,
what Huo Wenhai did was perfectly
understandable.
Before we fight a common enemy, we must ensure there's no in-fighting.
The Mystic Nine is a threat.
This cannot have come from you.
It's unlike you.
Of course it wasn't me.
But
you are supposed to get rid of the Mystic Nine,
yet you still haven't done that.
You put me in a difficult situation.
The current situation
solves both our conundrums.
As I said,
this is going to happen to the Mystic Nine one day.
But the Mystic Nine helped to sabotage
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama's plan.
If the Mystic Nine is eradicated,
other sects in the city
will take up arms and attack
the Ministry of War.
It will jeopardize
future governance.
That's my excuse
to tell Huo Wenhai
to just capture all of you, not kill.
But the higher-up now knows
that the Mystic Nine has been captured.
If the execution order comes through,
I won't be able to stop it.
Luo Ang.
I know you hold onto your principles
more so than I do.
If the Ministry of War makes an order,
you'll see it through.
But we are close friends.
Can you spare the Mystic Nine?
If you had followed my advice
and dealt with the Mystic Nine accordingly,
I would have let this slide.
But Huo Wenhai now wants
the Mystic Nine gone.
And you can't do anything about it.
If you want to spare the Mystic Nine...
Unless
Huo Wenhai commits a violation.
Then, you become the special commissioner
who deals with the Mystic Nine.
That way,
you'll have the chance to find a loophole.
It's a military order.
Whether Huo Wenhai
or I execute it,
what difference does it make?
Zhang Qishan.
If you get rid of the Mystic Nine,
you'll be doing the Ministry of War a favor.
You're siding with it.
Naturally, the ministry will think highly of you.
After all these years,
the higher-up is no longer sure
if you're the Mystic Nine
or the defense commander.
To put it bluntly,
if the Mystic Nine falls,
you have to die as well.
But that's not the outcome I want.
You are an excellent soldier.
You should die on the battlefield.
Xie Jiu has confessed.
He said he was forced
to work with the Japanese.
The one who coerced him
was Changsha Special Commissioner,
Huo Wenhai.
When I submit evidence of their collusion
to the Ministry of War,
you will become
the special commissioner.
Xie Jiu
has already committed suicide in the cell.
What?
[To Master Zhang, From Xie]
He left this letter to you.
Don't let him die in vain.
[To Master Zhang, From Xie]
Master Zhang.
When you're reading this,
I'm probably gone.
Do not avenge me.
Master Zhang.
My fate is sealed.
I die willingly.
Do not worry about me.
Remember.
The time is running out for the Mystic Nine.
You have two options.
One,
defy the military order
and protect the Mystic Nine.
Luo Ang
will reinstate Huo Wenhai.
Huo Wenhai will not show mercy,
and the Mystic Nine will fall.
What about my second option?
Kill six to protect three.
No way.
Don't jump to conclusions.
Listen to me.
You know
I will not do this
just to protect myself.
Zhang Qishan.
Do you
really want to sit and watch how they
get rid of the Mystic Nine?
The Mystic Nine.
Kill six clans
to protect three clans.
The Ministry of War
and I agreed on this.
It's the limit
of their leniency.
Xie Jiu.
I know you have a plan.
Help me again.
Master Zhang.
Our killer isn't
the Ministry of War.
It's the status quo.
You are a smart man.
You know the right decision to make.
Do not be carried away by your emotion.
Without the Mystic Nine,
the world wouldn't be as peaceful now!
I will not let them down.
If I must sacrifice myself
to keep the Mystic Nine safe...
Master Zhang.
I'm running out of time.
You already know
which six clans
to eliminate.
Right?
Eryue Hong must be spared.
Huo Xiangu must be spared.
One is a renowned opera actor.
The other has a clan full of women.
If the Ministry of War
kills them,
there'll be a public outrage,
or even a riot.
You are a Japanese sympathizer.
So you're destined to die.
Chen Pi is a thug.
Heibei is a murderer.
Li is a gangster.
Tiezui...
None of them can live.
But you're different, Master Zhang.
You have to fight our invader.
We cannot kill Laogou.
He has saved so many people.
He's also a thug.
Wu Laogou has to die.
Master Zhang.
The Mystic Nine is old.
We can't carry on anymore.
But you
must forge on with those
who live.
Don't look back.
To Ninth Master.
Does he
not have a better plan?
He sacrificed his life to set up everything.
He wouldn't have done this
if there was a better plan.
Perhaps
we can just disband the Mystic Nine?
In Changsha and its neighboring provinces,
there are more than 100,000 people
under the Mystic Nine.
How can we disband it?
Master Zhang.
Do you have a plan?
Threaten Luo Ang to spare the Mystic Nine.
After the Mystic Nine leave Changsha,
I'll convince Luo Ang
not to drag all of you into this.
Then, I'll head to Nanjing
to receive my punishment.
That means you'll be going against
the Ministry of War.
You will be suspended, or even executed.
Ninth Master will die in vain.
That's good.
I can see him
and apologize to him.
Master Zhang.
I can do all this for you.
Then, you'll just say
I've gone rogue
and have me executed.
To put everything to an end,
I have to die.
My death
will convince the Ministry of War
that the Mystic Nine will not rise again.
I won't let this happen.
Remember
when we first met?
I asked
what you would do when all hope seemed lost.
[Ancient Zhang's Residence, Northeastern China]
Traitors
don't deserve a face.
[Traitor]
Outsider.
I have spared you.
You shouldn't be here.
Do you want to live?
You can try
escaping once more.
Do you want to live?
If you want to live,
I'll save you.
Do you want to live or not?
I want to live.
I'll come with you.
Will they catch up to us?
If they do,
we're done for.
Don't worry.
The Zhang Clan is a mess now.
Their internal issues will keep them occupied.
They don't have time
for outsiders like us.
Why did you save me?
You are from the Zhang Clan's principal family.
Why
did you run away?
Because...
Because I couldn't stand my clan
anymore.
I wanted freedom.
That's why I saved you.
♪The prophecy once foretold♪
Thank you for saving me.
Get up.
♪Ask those who've joined♪
If you trust me,
you can follow me.
Perhaps
we'll find a new path for us.
I'll come with you.
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
What is your name?
I'm...
Xiaoyu.
You'll be Xiaoyu from now on.
Zhang Xiaoyu.
A fish is free.
You are free.
Master Zhang.
I am a traitor
expelled by my clan.
Why did you save me?
Because you said you wanted to live.
I'm not one
to look at one's past.
I only see the future.
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
Take good care of others.
Master Zhang.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who is lucky enough to reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
Master Zhang.
Forgive me.
♪But this could♪
I am a traitor through and through.
[To Zhang Xiaoyu]
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
Dear Adjutant Xiaoyu,
the survival of the Mystic Nine
is upon us.
I have a way to keep the Mystic Nine alive.
We kill six clans to save three clans.
But Master Zhang will not comply.
And he will die for it.
If you want to save Master Zhang,
you need to do three things for me.
One,
immobilize Master Zhang for at least one day.
Two, you must kill Huo Wenhai.
Huo Wenhai has a private army.
Something's afoot.
If you don't kill him, he will change everything.
Three, do not break into the prison
to save the Mystic Nine.
I have another plan for that.
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave♪
♪The raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please♪
♪Do take care of yourself♪
Sir.
Have we found Wu Laogou and the rest?
No updates so far.
But Sir,
Zhang Xiaoyu is here. He wishes to see you.
He drugged Zhang Qishan
and wants to negotiate with you.
Zhang Xiaoyu?
Zhang Qishan
is getting impatient.
He's using such a cheap
trick.
Does he want to kill me that badly?
Zhang Xiaoyu is betraying him?
Does he even believe it himself?
I shall turn him down then.
No.
Let him in.
I want to see
what trick he has.
Bring the men from Xiangxi too.
I'll make sure he won't get out alive.
Yes.
[Changsha Defense Headquarters]
You even brought
Zhang Qishan's military seal.
You sure
have gone out of your way.
I stole it.
How loyal of you.
Commander Huo,
can we talk now?
After all, it concerns
your life.
Tell me.
You'd better be telling the truth.
Do you know
what Officer Luo and Master Zhang
talked about?
Tell me.
He didn't return to Changsha
for official business.
He came back to rescue someone.
He did it to rescue Master Zhang
so that Master Zhang can continue working for the Ministry of War.
He wants Master Zhang to eliminate the Mystic Nine
personally as proof of allegiance.
That way,
the Ministry of War no longer has a thorn in their side.
But it's at the cost
of your life.
Xie Jiu committed suicide by drinking poison.
Before he died, he left a letter
saying that he and you worked for the Japanese.
After you surrender your position,
Master Zhang can take over
as the new special commissioner, replacing you.
He'll have the power to eliminate the Mystic Nine.
You're trying to drive a wedge between us.
Do you think
I'll take your word
at face value?
You know very well
if I'm telling the truth or not.
If what you're saying is true,
isn't that
what you want as well?
Why did you
come here today?
People like us
followed him back then
and fought our way out of Northeastern China.
Every time, we put our necks
on the line for him.
In the end,
he decides to sacrifice
all of us
to save the Mystic Nine.
Then shouldn't you
kill Zhang Qishan right away?
Master Zhang saved me.
I will not harm him.
But Wu Laogou,
Huo Xiangu, and Qi Tiezui
are all missing.
I know where they are.
Before Master Zhang returned,
he gave them a place to stay.
Right now,
they are in an old military site
at the northwestern part of the city.
[Traitor]
Master Zhang.
I will never
betray you again.
[Xuanzhen Temple]
Sir,
is there a letter for me
here?
The man who left this letter
said you were illiterate.
So I shall read it to you.
Thank you.
Fifth Master, I hope this letter finds you well.
When you're reading this,
I'm probably already dead.
The Mystic Nine is destined to fall.
Ninth Master.
Laogou.
It is inescapable that the Ministry of War
will eliminate the Mystic Nine.
Master Zhang
will use his life
to threaten the Ministry of War
to spare us.
But that
is merely prolonging the inevitable.
The Mystic Nine will not let Master Zhang die.
The war needs him.
Therefore,
when they execute Master Zhang,
to save him,
the Mystic Nine will return
to break him out.
When that happens,
all of us will die.
Look no further than the story of Water Margin
to know what happened to those who tried to break the prisoner out.
We
should be the heroes in the story.
Tell me.
What is your plan?
You hold the key
to our plan.
You're overestimating me.
I raise dogs. That's all.
Fifth Master,
you're so much better than you think.
Everyone worships Master Zhang like a deity.
But a deity is not a mortal.
He doesn't know how to love like a mortal does.
But Fifth Master, you are a mortal.
That's why
only you can save the people.
Only you can save the deity.
I can't.
I kill the deity.
Exactly.
That is precisely the reason.
Among the Mystic Nine,
you're the one who despises our ways the most,
the one who can't stand the Mystic Nine.
Everyone in Changsha City knows that.
Therefore,
you have to become
the head of the Mystic Nine.
That way, the Ministry of War
will think
that when they kill you,
the other clans
will not return to save you.
Then, most people in the Mystic Nine
will be safe.
Only you
can save us from this predicament.
You want me to sacrifice myself
for the Mystic Nine?
Why should I do that?
If you do not help us,
the Mystic Nine will lose the protection afforded by Master Zhang.
Thousands of our members
will be executed by the Ministry of War.
The women and the vulnerable will be expelled from Changsha,
left to their own devices.
I believe
you don't want
to see that happen.
You're threatening me now.
It's the reality.
Of course,
you can choose to ignore all this.
Even if I agree to this,
according to the rules in the Mystic Nine,
I have to kill the previous master
to take over their position.
Do you want me to kill every master
in the Mystic Nine?
No need to kill.
Just render them useless.
But
the Ministry of War has already infiltrated the Mystic Nine.
Each clan
has spies from the Ministry of War.
Hence,
you must hit where it hurts the most
so that the Ministry of War will believe
that they no longer
pose a threat.
Like how?
For example,
turn Eryue Hong into a cripple
so that
he can no longer perform.
Xie Jiu, you're insane!
That's no different from killing him.
The Ministry of War won't believe you
unless you go that far.
When that happens,
no one in the Mystic Nine can live.
Fifth Master.
Sacrifice a few lives
or
the thousands of lives in the Mystic Nine?
The masters of Mystic Nine
saved my life
in Xinyue Restaurant.
Is this how I repay
their kindness?
Saving our lives is simple.
I have plenty of ways.
What's difficult
is saving thousands of lives.
Save a thousand lives
or save nine lives.
You decide.
You know
what kind of person I am.
That's why you're asking for my help.
The Mystic Nine is on its last breath.
It is an emergency.
Hesitation will lead to irreversible changes.
Fifth Master.
I
count on you for the survival of the Mystic Nine.
That's so unfair.
Did God let me join the Mystic Nine
so that
I can die for them instead?
Sir.
There's an uproar.
All news outlets are reporting
about Changsha's curfew and their manhunt for cultists.
But the evidence shows
that there is no cultist at all.
[Curfew]
They say the Ministry of War
framed the righteous people.
The rumor is spreading like wildfire.
The city was locked down for two days
and the news has traveled
to Nanjing and Shanghai.
Someone is expediting the process.
Sir,
if this carries on,
the higher-up will do more
than just questioning us.
We must lift the curfew
and release the masters
of Mystic Nine.
Sure.
It's time to let them go.
Yes.
[Notice]
No more curfew in Changsha.
The masters of Mystic Nine
have been released.
[It is done.]
[Your trouble is gone for now.]
We can finally go back.
[Take care.]
Great.
Where's Wu Laogou?
Laogou is...
Laogou!
[Pear Garden]
[Closed]
Laogou.
Didn't you leave Changsha
with Master Zhang already?
Where is Master Zhang?
The Ministry of War wants the Mystic Nine gone.
They spared us this time,
but it won't last long.
Next time,
they'll kill us.
Laogou.
Leave Changsha
when you still have the chance.
I will take my wife with me
to the west.
What about you?
What's your plan?
I
joined the Mystic Nine.
I finally became one of the top brass.
I'm not going to leave.
Second Master,
I haven't thanked you properly yet.
When I first joined the Mystic Nine,
I thought you'd look down on a dog breeder
like me.
To my surprise, you brought me business,
thus allowing me to find my footing in Changsha.
I'll always remember
this favor from you.
A toast
to you.
It's all in the past.
But I need to mention something from the past.
After all,
I joined the Mystic Nine
because of you.
Perhaps you do not know.
Back then,
I was down there, below the stage.
I watched your troupe
perform
a popular opera
called Havoc in Heaven.
Moreover,
in Xiangyuan Mine,
many laborers were exploited.
I begged the masters of the Mystic Nine
to save the people.
I even
visited your residence.
Do you know
what your man said?
The Second Master of the Mystic Nine
is not someone a nobody could see.
Yes.
I was a nobody back then.
I didn't have the right
to see you.
Who was I
to defend the common folks?
I wasn't aware
of this.
When did that happen?
It
will never reach your ears anyway.
This door of yours
separates two worlds.
How much mortal suffering will you see
sitting behind this door?
So
I understand why the Monkey King
wreaked havoc in heaven.
I also understand that only by
joining the top brass
can I achieve what an ordinary person cannot.
Laogou.
What
are you getting at?
Listen.
After I joined the Mystic Nine,
I found out that top brass like you
did not put your talent to good use.
You fight among each other,
and do nothing if something bad happens.
Do you care
about the ordinary folks?
Have you thought
about delivering them from their misery?
I don't think so.
None of you ever did.
It begins here, so it shall end here.
I returned here
to wreak havoc in heaven.
I will
eliminate you so-called deities
one by one.
The first one
is you, Eryue Hong.
Don't move.
Or you'll die even quicker.
The poison is still in your body, isn't it?
The liquor is not poisoned.
I merely added
something that boosts your blood circulation
so that it activates
the toxin in your body.
Laogou.
What are you trying to do?
Laogou!
You've gone insane!
Humans
cannot escape love, it seems.
You are the Second Master of the Mystic Nine.
How could you let yourself be imprisoned
by your feelings?
You let yourself turn rusty,
giving the Ministry of War a chance to infiltrate us.
You
brought this upon yourself.
No!
No...
Put it down.
No.
No!
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪